Xavier University Department of Education records
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections
Xavier University Department of Education records
1964-2002
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections Phone: 513-745-4821 http://www.xavier.edu/cm/archives
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Department of Education
1.5 linear feet (3 boxes)
This is a collection of documents originating with the Xavier University Department of Education.
XUA-77
History of Xavier University Department of Education
In 2006 the Xavier University Department of Education became the School of Education which encompassed different departments. As of May, 2015 the departments represented in the School of Education are: the Department of Secondary and Special Education, the Department of Educational Leadership and Human Resource Development, and the Department of Childhood Education and Literacy. The Department of School and Community Counseling which at one time was part of the School of Education later became the Department of Counseling (apart from the School of Education) in the College of Social Sciences, Health, and Education.
Scope and Content
Documents in this collection include meeting minutes, correspondence, reports and proposals.
Statement of Arrangement
Materials are arranged into the following series:
Meeting Minutes, Correspondence, and Reports
Montessori Education Program
Brochures, Pamphlets, and Other Publications
State of Ohio Reports and Evaluations
Proposal for Doctor of Education Program
Related Material
Materials received from the current Xavier University School of Education will be held separately under that school's records.
Restrictions on Access
Some materials may have restricted access. Please contact the archives staff.
Accruals
Additions to this collection are anticipated.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects:
Education--Study and teaching
Detailed Description of The Collection
- Meeting Minutes, Correspondence, and Reports, 1972-1997
  - Minutes, Correspondence, Reports, 1972-1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, Correspondence, Reports, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, Correspondence, Reports, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, Correspondence, Reports, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, Correspondence, Reports, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, Correspondence, Reports, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, Correspondence, Reports, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, Correspondence, Reports, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, Correspondence, Reports, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Montessori Education Program, 1964-1991
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1964-1967 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1971-1991 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Brochures, Pamphlets, and Other Publications, undated
  - Brochures, Pamphlets, and Publications, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- State of Ohio Reports and Evaluations, 1975-1991
  - Report to Ohio Department of Education: Teacher Certification, 1975 April (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - State of Ohio On Campus Evaluation of Teacher Education Program, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - State of Ohio On Site Evaluation of Teacher Education Program, 1979; 1983 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - State of Ohio On Site Evaluation of Teacher Education Program, 1989; 1991 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Proposal for Doctor of Education Program, 2001-2002
  - Proposal for Doctor of Education Program to Ohio Board of Regents, 2001 February (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Proposal for Doctor of Education Program to North Central Association, 2002 September (Box 3, Folder 4)